Guide to the Edward C. Sturges, collector, International Order of Good Templars records,1845-1978.
International Order of Good Templars records, Edward C Sturges, collector
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edward C. Sturges, collector, International Order of Good Templars records, 1845-1978.
2573
Edward C., Sturges 1878-1963,
24.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Memorabilia, Photographs, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files of the International (originally "Independent") Order of Good Templars.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Attorney; Deputy Commissioner, New York State Department of Transportation and Finance; Grand Chief Templar, New York State (1961); and IOGT officer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files of the International (originally "Independent") Order of Good Templars include correspondence (1901-59) of Sturges, National Chief Templar Ben D. Wright, Laura R. Church, D.W. McNeil, Tom Honeyman, C. Wilmer King, and other officers and members regarding IOGT business and related subjects; appeals by members against actions taken by Grand Lodges with related correspondence (1914-29); typescript and MS. notes pertaining to the history of the IOGT and the organization, history, and membership of various lodges; minutes, financial records, and membership lists (26 vols. and loose items, 1871-1957) of lodges in Albany and Niagara Counties and elsewhere, mainly in New York State; printed lodge constitutions (ca. 1855-1919); notes (5 vols., ca. 1866-ca. 1906) pertaining to changes in the constitution of the Grand Lodge of New York; journals of proceedings and officers' reports (1856-1978) for the Grand Lodge of New York and other national and regional lodges; books of ritual and degree and many brochures, pamphlets, and books concerning temperance, prohibition, and the IOGT; publications including the NATIONAL TEMPERANCE ADVOCATE (1870-1873), the OFFICIAL ORGAN and its successor, the NEW YORK TEMPLAR AND OFFICIAL ORGAN (1883-1942, incomplete), the INTERNATIONAL GOOD TEMPLAR (1888-1962, incomplete), and the NATIONAL GOOD TEMPLAR (1910-12, 1938-62, incomplete); IOGT certificates and blank forms; and photographs, including one of William Jennings Bryan.
Also, personal papers, mainly drafts and typescript and mimeographed copies of Sturges' remarks (March 11, 1930) questioning the constitutionality of the Eighteenth Amendment at a hearing before the Judiciary Committees of the New York State Legislature, as well as his correspondence and suggestions for the revision of that amendment.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sturges, Edward C.,1878-1963,; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.; Church, Laura R.; Honeyman, Tom.; King, C. Wilmer.; McNeil, D. W.; Wright, Ben D.; International Order of Good Templars.; International Order of Good Templars.Grand Lodge of New York.; International Order of Good Templars.National Grand Lodge.
Subjects:
Alcohol--Law and legislation.; Prohibition.; Social movements.; Temperance--Societies, etc.; Lawyers.
Places:
New York (State)--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a copy of an older paper guide. PDF file.
- Grand Lodge: By Laws/Constitution (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Grand Lodge: By Laws/Constitution (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Items Related to Constitutions, 1907-1932 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Grand Lodge of the United States Financial Reports, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Appeals (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Appeals (cont'd) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- I.G.O.T. Blanks and Certificates, 1926-1962 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lodge Organization (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Good Templar History (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes on Lodge Membership, 1959 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Research Notes for I.G.O.T. and Other Fraternal Organizations (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Grand Lodge of California (Box 1, Folder 12)
- League to Enforce Peace and Congress for a League of Nations-and printed items, 1919 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Prohibition-Reports and Minutes, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- By-laws/Membership/Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Supreme Court, Albany County (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Program Record (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Baron-English National Rite (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1901-March 1936 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, April 1936-1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Edward Sturges' Personal Papers (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Edward Sturges' Personal Papers (cont'd) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Edward Sturges' Personal Papers (cont'd) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Newspapers and Clippings, 1881-1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous, 1906-1958 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Photographs, 1851-1905 and N.D. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- I.O.G.T. - The Bulletin, Sept, 1960-Sept, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- I.O.G.T. - Journal of Proceedings, 1957, 1958, 1960, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- I.O.G.T.-Fifty Years-The Eastern Grand Lodge (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Master of Temperance Literature Certificate, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Group and member photographs, 1900-1905 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Paperweight with photo of Temperance officer Charles Gildersleeve, Undated; MU-2516 (Box 1)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Meeting Minutes, 1883-1887 (Box 2)
- Albany County Lodges: Quarterly Returns, Membership List, Secretary's Report, Receipts, Report of Committee on Credentials, 1884-1912 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Meeting Minutes, 1912 (Box 2)
- Albany County Lodges: Misc. Papers, 1912-1915 (Box 2)
- Treasure Council, Membership List, 1880-1898 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Financial Records, Quarterly Reports, 1887-1888 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Receipts, Membership Lists, Financial Secretary's Report, 1891-1892 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Financial Records, Quarterly Reports, 1891-1914 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Receipts, Membership Lists, Financial Secretary's Report, 1894-1895 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Receipts, Membership Lists, Financial Secretary's Report, 1899-1901 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Meeting Minutes, Secretary's Report, Membership List, Receipts, 1899-1901 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Financial Records, Quarterly Reports, 1899-1909 (Box 2)
- Albany County Lodge: Quarterly Tax, Subscriptions, Officer List, 1899-1910 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Receipts, Membership List, Financial Secretary Reports, 1901-1906 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Meeting Minutes, 1901-1902 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Altamont NY, Meeting Minutes, 1902-1904 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Receipts, Membership List, Financial Secretary Reports, 1907-1909 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Receipts, Membership List, Financial Secretary Reports, 1909-1912 (Box 2)
- Triumph Lodge: Receipts, Membership List, Financial Secretary Reports, 1911-1914 (Box 2)
- Albany County Lodge: Meeting Minutes, N.D. (Box 3)
- Albany County Lodge: Meeting Minutes, 1871-1887 (Box 3)
- Albany County Secretary's Book: Quarterly Returns, County Lodge Minutes, Secretary's Report, Receipts, Report of Committee on Credentials, 1888-1898 (Box 3)
- Albany County Secretary's Book: Quarterly Returns, County Lodge Minutes, Secretary's Report, Receipts, Report of Committee on Credentials, 1896-1905 (Box 3)
- Albany County Secretary's Book: Quarterly Returns, Niagara District Minutes, Secretary's Report, Receipts, Report of Committee on Credentials, 1909-1922 (Box 3)
- Albany County Secretary's Book: Quarterly Returns, Niagara District Minutes, Secretary's Report, Receipts, Report of Committee on Credentials, 1924-1948 (Box 3)
- Saratoga County Lodge: Membership List, 1889-1934 (Box 3)
- Albany County Lodge Report, 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Special Constitution of Albany County Lodge and By-Laws, No. 22, N.D. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lockport City Lodge: Quarterly Returns, April-May, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Albany County Lodge: Benefit Fund Membership Certificates and Receipts, 1904-1908 (Box 3)
- Order of Business and Grand Officers' Reports for Grand Lodge Session I.O.G.T., Aug-56 (Box 4)
- Order of Business and Grand Officers' Reports for Grand Lodge Session I.O.G.T., Aug-57 (Box 4)
- Order of Business and Grand Officers' Reports for Grand Lodge Session I.O.G.T., Jul-58 (Box 4)
- Officers' Advance Reports: National Grand Lodge, 1936 (Box 4)
- Officers' Advance Reports: National Grand Lodge, 1936 (Box 4)
- Officers' Advance Reports: National Grand Lodge, 1957 (Box 4)
- Officers' Advance Reports: National Grand Lodge, 1957 (Box 4)
- Hand Book of Good Templary by Prof G.W.E. Hill, 1897 (Box 4)
- Why He Wears the Templar's Badge by Rev. T.F. Parker, 1898 (Box 4)
- 31 Years of Good Templary, 1899 (Box 4)
- Fifty Years of Good Templar Work in England by Joseph Malins, N.D. (Box 4)
- Patriotic No-License Songster for use at No-License Rallies and Temperance Meetings of All Kinds-by Rev. O.R. Miller, 1906 (Box 4)
- Report of Committee on Revision, Aug-07 (Box 4)
- Report of Committee on Revision, Aug-08 (Box 4)
- Officers of the National Grand Lodge, 1909-1910 (Box 4)
- World's Temperance Centennial Congress, 1908 (Box 4)
- 45th Annual Convention: Woman's Christian Temperance Union of the State of NY, Oct-18 (Box 4)
- Program: Good Templar Day, Aug-39 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet: I.O.G.T., 1942 (Box 4)
- Program: Official Visit to the Grand Lodge of NY by International Chief Templar, Jul-51 (Box 4)
- Program: 100th Anniversary of the Grand Lodge of NY, Jul-52 (Box 4)
- Journal of Proceedings: World Congress: Holland, Jul-58 (Box 4)
- Albany County Lodge: Miscellaneous Notes, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- I.O.G.T. Pamphlets, N.D. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous I.O.G.T. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous I.O.G.T. (continued) (Box 5, Folder 4)